Hello, and welcome back. This week we are going to be talking
大家好 欢迎回来 这周我们将讨论
about image and video inpainting. In contrast with the topics that we
图像与视频的修复 上周我们讨论了许多几何相关的话题
described last week, where we performed a description of fundamental tools to solve
学习了一些基础知识 以此作为工具来解决问题
a number of problems, like an isotropic diffusion, active contours, and even
这些问题包括 各向异性扩散 主动轮廓 以及图像修复
image inpainting. This week is about a particular problem.
在这周的课程中 我们要解决一个特定的问题
It's not about tools for multiple problems,
我们不再讨论解决多个问题的工具
it's about solving one particular problem in image and video processing.
而只针对图像和视频处理中的一个特定问题
Of course, some of the tools that we are going to be using for this might be used
当然 我们接下来所用的工具很可能
for other techniques, and we often learn from the solutions of
也在其它技术中被使用到 我们经常从某个问题的解决方案中
a problem towards another problem. But it's a very important difference
得到启发 从而解决了另一个问题
between providing for the mental tools for solving multiple problems, and
但是在解决多类问题与特定问题上 其基本工具是有很大差别的
solving one particular problem. So what is image and video inpainting?
那到底什么是视频图像修复呢？
And let's start with image inpainting. Image inpainting is basically the art of
让我们从图像修复开始 图像修复是一种
changing an image in a non-detectable form.
采用让人无法察觉的方式来处理图像的技术
So here we see a painting that has a lot of degradation, and here is the
我们看到这幅油画有很多破损的地方
restoration of that painting. This was of course done by professionals
这是修复后的油画 当然 这是专业人员人工修复的
manually. It's a painting, it's not a picture, was
这是一幅油画 而不是计算机中的图片
not done in the computer, although the computer can help as well, as we're
它没有经过计算机处理 当然 计算机也可以帮助处理油画 这一点
going to see it later on. When you go and see this picture in the
我们接下来会学习到 当我们在博物馆里看到这幅油画时
museum, you'll believe it's the original picture.
我们会相信 这就是原作
Some experts actually might be able to notice the difference, and be able to see
一些专家可能会注意到画面的异样 甚至能发现
the regions that were actually inpainted or filled in with information from
油画中的一些区域是被人工修复的 或是从另一些区域中复制来填充的
different regions. But the basic idea is that in inpainting,
但是 修复的基本概念是这样的
we show you an image or a video, and we make you believe that's the original one.
当我展示修复后的图像或视频时 大家会相信那就是它原来的样子
In this case, it's to solve degradations. Inpainting, it's sometimes also called
在这个例子中 就是要去解决破损问题 所以 修复有时也被称为
fill in, because we're filling in the regions of
填补 因为我们根据区域的周围信息来
problems, the regions of deterioration with
填补问题区域 或者说是破损区域
informations from this surrounding. And we are going to see that, sometimes,
我们有时会从附近区域来获取信息
with fill in with information from the near areas sometimes with information
有时又会从整幅图像的较远区域来获取信息
from far away areas from the whole image. There's even techniques that do image in
甚至有一些技术在修复图像时
painting using database of images where you look for similar things.
从图像的数据库中寻找相似的区域来修复图像
So, this is one example of what image in painting needs to be done.
这是一个图像修复的例子 它告诉我们图像修复做了什么
Remember, it's modifying an image in a non-detectable form.
请记住 它以一种让人无法察觉的方式修复了图像
And when we say non-detectable, we say at least by the non-experts.
而这里的无法察觉 是指对于非专业人士而言无法察觉
Here is another example. A lot has been done to this image, basically to
这是另外一个例子 我们对这幅图像已经做了许多处理
transform it into this one. Of course it has been inpainted, you see
从而得到了这幅图像 当然它已经被修复了
these regions have been filled in. But also there were color corrections and
可以看到这些区域已经被填补了 而且还做了颜色校正和其它处理
other things, but this illustrates yet another example of image inpainting.
尽管如此 它仍然是描述图像修复的一个很好的例子
Look at all these regions that have missing information and that were
我们来看看这些丢失信息的区域
basically restored, inpainted, filled in with nice information that looks like
依据图像中其它区域的信息 它们已经被修复了
natural in the surrounding region of the image.
而且修补后的区域在整幅图像中十分自然
Of course, it's natural to extend these to regular photography, in particular
当然 我们可以将这种技术扩展到日常摄影图片的处理中
when we were talking about pictures, and not digital pictures, but analog
特别是当处理胶片摄影照片时 而不是数码摄影的照片
pictures, and here we see examples. Some of examples like here have a few
这里有一些例子 它们有些包含了另外一些修复技术
additional restoration techniques, but we see these.
我们可以看看这些区域
For example, the picture was turned into two pieces, then was put together and to
具体来说 这张照片分成了两部分 然后被拼在一起
repair that, you basically see that it was inpainted.
经过修复处理后 我们可以看到它已经被修复好了
A region of missing information or undesirable information was filled in
丢失了信息和含有欠佳信息的区域
with other types of information. We see here the same.
被其它类型的信息填补了 这里也是一样的
There is a scratch. Now the scratch is gone.
这里有一道刮痕 而现在刮痕被去除了
And here there is a similar example like this.
这个例子与之相似
Basically, the picture was folded, and when you unfold it, you see this kind of
这张照片被折叠过 当重新展开这张照片时 会发现
scratch in the middle and then here its gone.
在照片中部有这种折痕 然后在这儿它被去除了
So, these are all examples of image impending to restore basically the image
总之 这些例子都是将有损的图像修复成更好看的样子
to a much nicer looking image. Of course, this is an example that we saw
这是我们在第一周的课程里见过的图片
in the first week, where image inpainting is done with a completely different
这里 图像修复做的事与先前的完全不同
target. In this case, and this illustrates the
在这个例子中 它阐释了图像修复的理想结果
idea of modifying an image in an undetectable form.
就是让人无法察觉到图像是被处理过的
In this case, we see nothing, nothing wrong with this image, that we know, if
在这个例子中 我们觉得这张照片没什么不对劲的
you remember from the first week of class, that basically this was the
但是我们知道 如果大家还记得 这才是原始图像
original image. So what was inpainted now is the object
所以 在这里进行了的修复是
that the user wants to remove from the image.
去除图片中用户不想让它出现的事物
So basically, this region becomes the region of missing information that we are
因此 这个区域就好像是丢失了信息的区域
going to inpaint in, and we need to recover the water, and we
我们需要修复这个区域 需要还原河水
need to recover the column. So we need to recover texture,
需要还原围栏 需要还原围栏的质地
we need to recover structure, straight lines and water that is
纹理和直线结构 以及水的曲线结构
basically non-straight lines. So very different types of informations
总之 许多不同类型的信息需要
need to be filled in, inpainted, in order to solve this problem of removing
被填补进来 从而把物体从图像中去除
objects. And we discuss in the first week, this is
并且 我们在第一周提过
used all the times in the movie industry, I show you a few examples of objects that
这是电影工业中一直使用的技术 我还举了一些例子
need to be removed in the movie industry. Here is yet another example from this
来阐释电影中需要被去除的物体 这是这个领域的另一个例子
era, where basically we see here, a picture of Lenin, and a picture, and next
我们看到这是一张列宁 (Lenin) 的照片 在他旁边站着的是
to him there is Trotsky. And here, basically, Trotsky has been
托洛茨基 (Trotsky) 而在这幅图中 托洛茨基被去除了
removed from the picture. So once again an object has been removed
所以 这又是一个从照片中去除物体的例子
from the picture. And, yeah, you can have multiple examples
并且 通过网络 我们可以找到许多这样的例子
of these. For example in this website, or the website that was linked in the
比如 大家可以访问这个网站 或者访问以往幻灯片中有关的网站
previous slide. So again inpainting in order to remove
总之 再说一遍 这里的修复
objects that from the image or from the video.
就是去除图像或视频中的物体
I want to explain something that inpainting, in its basic form, cannot do.
我现在解释一下 因其基本形式的局限性 图像修复不能解决所有问题
I don't want to, you have the wrong understanding that inpainting is an
我不想让大家错误地认为 图像修复是
extremely smart technique that can fill in with whatever you want.
一种极其智能化的 可以填补任何我们所需 的技术
So let me use this example to illustrate that.
所以 我用这个例子来说明这一点
Here, this person was removed, and then it was inpainted.
这儿的一个人被去除了 然后空白的区域被填补了
So when you look at this image, it holds everything that inpainting is about,
当观察这幅图像时 大家可以发现它承载了图像修复的所有概念
modifying the image in an undetectable form.
图像的修正让人无法察觉
But look what happened here. When the person was removed, two chairs
但是看看这儿发生了什么 当人物被去除后
were brought in. This is done by an expert.
两张椅子出现了 这是专家做的处理
It's not done by the computer. There's no way for the computer to
而不是计算机做的 计算机不可能理解
understand that what you want here are chairs.
我们想让这里出现椅子
Maybe in a very, very advanced technique, when you basically provide a lot of side
也许当用户提供了足够多的辅助信息 并使用了先进的技术时
information, you could, in the computer, with programs
就可以在计算机中 用像 Photoshop 这样的软件
like Photoshop, cut chairs from here and put them here.
完成复制这些椅子到这儿的操作
And this is the kind of stuff that was done here.
实际上 在这个例子中就是这样做的
So it's a cut and paste, and we are going to see how to do that.
剪切和粘贴椅子 在接下来的视频中 我们会学到怎么实现它
But basically, inpainting, does not have that high level knowledge of what needs
但是 修复技术其实并非如此智能 它不知道这儿需要出现什么
to be there. The computer and the user can interact to
用户与计算机之间需要交互才能将
basically bring that into the scene, as we're going to see later on.
椅子放到图像中 我们会在以后了解这些
But if you don't interact, if you just say, do something with this
但是 如果我们不与计算机交互 而只是对计算机说 处理一下这个区域
region, the computer does not know what is that
计算机并不知道我们要做什么
you want, why is that you want chairs there,
不知道我们为什么要在这填补椅子
and not, for example, green, not, for example, some of the background.
而为什么不是用绿色或者一些背景来填补
But with interaction with the user, we might be able to do this,
但是通过与用户的交互 就可以完成
kind of a cut and paste. So, this is about image inpainting.
这类剪贴操作 这就是我关于图像修复的补充说明
In the next video, I'm going to show you that we are actually familiar, in nature,
在下一个视频中 我会展示一些自然界中
with image and video inpainting, and that's actually very interesting.
类似图像修复的现象 那些都非常有意思
See you in the next video. Thank you very much.
下一个视频再见 非常感谢大家 // 果壳教育无边界字幕组 | 玉米Yummy |  luoyetx | 林小七Lynn